## Summary

Inspired by the Digital World, since 2008 I have been helping companies to build winning solutions and stand out from the competition. With a solid background that goes from visual and graphic design to frontend development, I create human-centric digital services focused on enhanced experiences.

From a strategic perspective, in the past couple of years, I have mastered my Product Designer skills by ensuring agile deliveries while incorporating Design Thinking techniques to match organizational requirements.

• Design Thinking approach into Digital Projects to match business strategies;

#### Main duties

- Development of solutions based in Design Sprint, Prototypes, User Journey and UX Research
- UX and UI to lead and improve new web products;

Check out my portfolio douglasnonato.com

### Main Skills

- Design Thinking
- User Experience
- UX Research
- User Journey
- User Interface (Figma)
- Product Strategy
- Project Management
- Product Discovery
- Data Analysis
- IoT

- SaaS
- Responsive Web Design
- Design Sprint
- WordPress
- Agile Methodologies
- Rapid Prototyping
- Front-End (HTML CSS JS)
- Adobe Creative Cloud
- Motion Design

## Career history

#### SENIOR UX DESIGNER

Whirlpool 03/2021 - Present

Owner of 17 brands (2022), Whirlpool is one of the largest home appliance manufacturers in the world with iconic brands present all around the globe.

#### **Activities:**

• Working directly with connected home appliances (IOT), I'm responsible for leading the design of 4 apps in the North America region and 3 in Europe.

### SENIOR PRODUCT DESIGNER

Sebrae

09/2018 - 03/2021

Sebrae is the largest business consultancy in Brazil. With over 700 offices across the country, Sebrae acts as a stimulating agent of entrepreneurship, helping in the competitiveness and sustainability of small enterprises, through training courses and partnerships with the public and private sectors.

#### **Activities:**

- Management of digital projects and bidding companies, applying Design Thinking approach to match business strategies;
- Development new services based in Design Sprints, Prototypes, User Journeys, and UX Research;
- UX and UI to lead and improve new web products.
- UX speaker at Sebrae events, videos, and publications;

#### Main projects I worked on:

- Institution's portal and e-commerce;
- Toolbox Sebrae;
- Mentoring network;
- Digital Community;
- App Meu Sebrae

#### PRODUCT DESIGNER

Beauty Date 07/2015 - 06/2018

Beauty Date's main service is the online booking, which connects customers to salons right in their phone screens, allowing them to book appointments whenever and wherever they want. In 2015 the startup received an investment of U\$8 million, and for 3 years I was able to act in this acceleration phase.

#### **Activities:**

- Lead new product features and improvements to the user experience; working both in research, UX and UI.
- Working with stakeholders such as Marketing, IT and C-Level.
- Development of Websites and Landing pages for new marketing campaigns;
- Front-end programming & Code review;
- Storyboard creation, 2D and 3D animations;

#### **WEB AND MOTION DESIGNER**

Promova Promoções e Eventos 08/2014 - 07/2015

Promotional marketing agency, with physical and digital brand activation services, such as event organization and booth manufacturing for fairs. It operates on a national level with offices in several cities in Brazil.

#### **Activities:**

- Concept design based on customer briefings;
- Website Development. Layout design and front-end programming;
- Promotional videos for: Concept presentation, architectural spaces and making-off;
- Storyboard creation, 2D and 3D animations, video shooting and soundtrack;

#### **UI AND UX DESIGNER**

QLance 02/2013 - 09/2013

Online platform for management of tournaments and events. Launched in 2013, the system was used by large university events.

#### **Activities:**

- UX and UI:
- Front-end programming.

#### **UI AND UX DESIGNER**

Agenda Beleza 08/2012 - 02/2013

The Agenda Beleza is a business platform for Beauty Services. It allows users to find professionals in the beauty industry and schedule the service. In addition, companies can promote online payment in order to guarantee the customer attendance, returning confidence through a discount.

#### **Activities:**

- UX and UI;
- Front-end programming.

#### DESIGNER

Provisuale *07/2009 - 03/2012* 

Provisuale was responsible for the largest Telecom, IT and Internet event in Latin America at the time, called Futurecom.

#### **Activities:**

- Designing events visual identity and printed materials;
- Development of hot sites. Layout and front-end programming;
- Production of promotional videos;
- Strategic and operational events planning;
- Contact with suppliers and management of outsourced team, ensuring the correct application of materials and activities before and during event days.

# Education, Certifications and Training



Post-graduation

**CREATIVE AND ENTREPRENEURIAL ECONOMY / 2020-2021** 

FAE Business School

**PRODUCT DISCOVERY** / 2021

PM3

**PRODUCT LEADERSHIP** / 2020

How Bootcamps

**DATA ANALYTIC** / 2019-2020

Infinitely

**SERVICE DESIGN** / 2019

Livework

**UX METRICS** / 2019

Mergo

**PROJECT MANAGER MOBILE** / 2018

Product Arena

**PROJECT MANAGER** / 2018

Aldeia Coworking

**ENGLISH CERTIFICATION** / 2017

TOEFL

**KANBAN** / 2015

Lean Kanban University

**IMMERSIVE ENGLISH COURSE** / 2013

BTC English



Bachelor of Arts (B.A.)

**GRAPHIC AND PRODUCT DESIGN** / 2008-2012

Faculdades Integradas do Brasil - UniBrasil

**WEB DESIGN** / 2007

Senac